Rory Hartong-Redden

August 13, 2024 | Boulder, CO | roryhr@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/rory-hartong-redden | roryhr.com

Summary

Senior Data Scientist with experience managing projects, performing statistical analysis, backend web development, and wrangling messy real-world data.

Skills

Programming Languages: Python, SQL, Shell DevOps: AWS, Docker, Terraform, CircleCI, Git

Data Processing: Postgres, Spark, Hadoop, S3

Data Science Tools: Scikit-learn, XGBoost, TensorFlow, pandas, PySpark, Matplotlib

Professional Experience

• SyBridge Technologies (Fast Radius)

Technical Manager and Senior Data Scientist

Boulder, CO

Aug 2021-May 2024

- Ensured revenue-critical API availability by developing high-quality code and comprehensive test suites, enabling \$10M per month in instant quotes
- Crafted SQL queries to collect training data, monitor model accuracy, and answer business questions
- Predicted shipping costs using mixed integer programming to pack boxes along with the UPS API
- Provided statistical analysis and visualization support for R&D projects involving manufacturing IoT data using Jupyter Notebooks with Python

• Fast Radius Chicago, IL

Data Scientist Feb 2020-Aug 2021

- Tech stack: Python, SQL, Scikit-learn, Flask, Docker, AWS ECS, Datadog
- As the founding data scientist, deployed the first machine learning model progressing from research to data munging to production deployment with Docker

• runtastic Linz, Austria
Data Engineer Oct 2018–Sep 2019

- Tech stack: Python, SQL, Spark, Hadoop, Flume, Oozie, Hive
- Led the design and deployment of a "People You Might Know" data product using Spark, scikitlearn, SparkML, and Elasticsearch

• Allstate

Research Analyst

Menlo Park, CA

Jul 2016–Sep 2018

- Tech stack: Python, pandas, TensorFlow, Spark, Julia, PostGIS
- Trained machine learning models and analyzed telematics and crash data for risk prediction
- Co-authored a research paper titled "Real-time Prediction of Intermediate-Horizon Automotive Collision" with the Stanford Intelligent Systems Lab

Education

• University of California, Santa Barbara

MS Mechanical Engineering

Santa Barbara, CA

Dec 2014

- Tech stack: MATLAB, SolidWorks, LATEX
- Thesis research: Designed and built an experiment to measure Faraday waves using a novel image processing technique for 3D high-speed mm-resolution measurement over a surface area of 225 cm²

• University of California, Santa Barbara

Santa Barbara, CA June 2010